<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Autumn School 2020</title>
    <link>/</link>
      <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Autumn School 2020</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Simeon Lisovski 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/logo-512x512.png</url>
      <title>Autumn School 2020</title>
      <link>/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary  program</title>
      <link>/program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/program/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;program.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consequences of changing seasonality across scales</title>
      <link>/project/seasonality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/seasonality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Seasonality is one of the most influencing pattern on earth. Global variation in seasonal climate is arguably the most dominant external driver in natural systems that underpins the formation of the earth’s biomes and almost all biological processes therein. Reproduction, food-web structures, host-pathogen interactions, movements, all vary with the seasons. Yet not only the living world is affected, geological processes such as erosion, river dynamics, earthquakes are somewhat driven or triggered by seasonal pattern such as snowmelt, monsoon and rainfall. And what about humans? Although we have largely decoupled our dependency on seasonal variation in climate, by e.g. using cloths that allow us to remain in cold hostile regions year-round and by exploiting global food resources. However certain aspects of our social and economic life are still meticulously tuned to global seasonality. And considering the recent COVID-19 crisis and natural seasonal variation on our immunocompetence, we are reminded once again how seasonality affects our life in the Anthropocene.With climate change, we don’t only see changes   (and mainly an increase) in the mean annual temperature, but we have also observed changes in the seasonal dynamics. For example, in many regions on the northern hemisphere, the summer period is becoming longer with shorter transitions (spring and autumn) and milder winters. In some regions the predictability changes with consequences for species that are adapted to highly predictable change (such as migratory birds or hibernating animals). Often the changes occurred in specific dimensions of the seasonal dynamic such as the start if the warmup or the monsoon. In other regions, we see changes in the length of the reproductive season coupled with higher primary productivity and a stronger difference between summer and winter temperatures. With such a high diversity of change, we expect an equal high diversity of consequences.  During the autumn school I would like to invite scientists from various fields and with a broad interest that may include economy and sociology and human health, as well as the climatology, geology and biological. Together I would like to discuss and develop a framework that allows describing what dimension of seasonality affect the various systems and what consequences we predict with ongoing climate change.Besides working towards a review (potentially data driven) and a conceptual framework for publication we could record our discussion, perform individual interviews during the discussion to later on show how we developed the ideas, what we struggle with and what our new insights are working together as an interdisciplinary team. This could become an outreach product accompanying a publication and illustrating out work within the Geo.X network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-person&#34;&gt;Contact person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simeon Lisovski (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:simeon.lisovski@awi.de&#34;&gt;simeon.lisovski@awi.de&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have you ever heard of Geoethics?</title>
      <link>/project/geoethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/geoethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What  is  Geoethics  and  does it  play a  role  in your  research?  During  this  week,  we willunderstand if and how geoethics play a role for us and if and how we should apply its conceptsto our research and to our working environment.The topics we deal with as fellows during our research are highly diverse and range from the thawing of the permafrost, the development of slums and biodiversity to earthquakes, flood protection   management   and   sustainable   transformation,   to   name   only   a   few   fields. Furthermore, we approach these topics with a wide variety of methods and theories. What they all have in common, however, is that they either deal with how humans influence the earth or how humans can be protected against/prepared for present and future changes on earth. And in this type of research we apply, often unconsciously, ethical assumptions about our relationship to the natural environment and to the society. And these assumptions are based  on  underlying  values  that  many  of  us  are  not  aware  of.  This  state  of  affairs  already  describes two of the four geoethical domains: our responsibility as geoscientists both to the natural environment and to society. The other two domains deal with us as individuals and as professionals in a working environment and can be applied to all scientists. Do we do good and  reliable  science?  Do  we  remain  objective?  Are  we  always  honest  with  our  data  and  results?  Do  we  work  together  with  a  respectful  attitude,  with  the  common  goal  of  finding  solutions  to  problems,  including  respect  for  the  ideas  of  others,  diversity  of  perspectives, exchange of information and data, respect for intellectual property?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The autumn school is the perfect place to learn and reflect on geoethics in our fields for the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We belong to the next generation of geoscientists who can actively influence how geoscientific practice will look like in the future.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are a diverse and interdisciplinary group of scientists,  able to cover many fields and bring different perspectives to the discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can directly apply one of the geoethical principles (from the societal domain) bycommunicating our results to the public in an understandable and easily accessible way.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result, at the end of the week,  we can expect an answer to the following questions: What does it mean nowadays to be a responsible geoscientist? How can we become and/or remainresponsible geoscientists?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-person&#34;&gt;Contact person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theresa Frommen&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to overcome the ‘maybe’ explanations of ‘why’: explaining causality?</title>
      <link>/project/causality/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/causality/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are proposing a “mini-research challenge” that would explore and gather methods for deriving and/or assigning directional influences, drivers, or causal links, particularly when undertaking remote sensing analysis or attributing climate adaptation. The question of “why” is inevitable when presenting a phenomenon detected or described.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*“Why are we seeing this/ why is this happening?”
*“Could this be because of a policy intervention?”
*“Could we say that this change we are seeing is linked to anthropogenic climate change?
*“Are farmers changing their cropping patterns because&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they’ve been they are trying to prevent weather&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;induced loss on a specific crop,-they’re trying to diversify their production and income,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;they’re neighbor convinced them to, or&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;because they learned a new cropping strategy at a farmer training program last season?”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How can we, researcher, enhance the certainty with which we answer this ‘why’? &amp;amp; can we draw causal links among observed phenomena?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obstacle of scientifically justifying the ‘why’ is not limited to the realm of short time series and climate adaptation studies. Challenges such as distinguishing and accounting (or controlling) for multiple factors driving a specified phenomenon, ‘random’ correlations, detecting the direction of statistical relationships, factors operating at multiple temporal and spatial scales and the formidable work of proving causality, are common across disciples. Within our working group on climate Adaptation in Agricultural Systems, some colleagues are dealing with these questions through statistical methods, some through triangulation with field work and others through forms of data integration. For example, one statistical method recently applied in our group to investigate climatic driver effects on wheat yield was a “causal discovery algorithm,” that adapts a variable selection method, with stricter requirements, to “eliminate spurious correlations,” through specifically addressing auto-correlation, indirect links, common drivers. However, when researcher from Geo.Society group face these challenges,  traditional algorithms or methods for causality often cannot be applied for local scale data or when dealing with shorter time-series, as is also the case for applications of the Sentinel sensors (launched in 2014).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We suppose that each field has their own way of dealing with these issues and we would like to learn how other Geo.X members have dealt with or are currently identifying causal links. The “expertise” for this research challenge would be drawn/ asked for in advanced primarily from Geo.X members. And would then workshop applications of these different schemes for explaining influences, drivers and causality into other cases (across Geo.X topics). There would not be a single, streamlined outcome, but rather a “cross-pollination” of methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This “mini-research challenge” has highly relevant outcomes to the Autumn School’s topic of science communication, as directional influences, drivers, or causal links all contribute to the ‘why’  andrelevance of research, building blocks for writing a narrative. Commonly the ‘why’  is framed in the introduction, interpreted in results, or hypothesizing in the discussion. In this “mini challenge,”  we could then explore how having a science-based justification of the ‘why’  can fortify any storyline, including e.g. a funding proposal or teaching &amp;amp; learning material.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-person&#34;&gt;Contact person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gina Maskell, Roopam Shukla
Potsdam Institute for Climate Impact Research&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Involving local communities interactively in the research stage ofdata acquisition</title>
      <link>/project/communityinteraction/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/communityinteraction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Permafrost is a phenomenon mainly observed in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s high latitudes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-person&#34;&gt;Contact person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Torben Windirsch-Woiwode, Tabea Rettelbach&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let the data talk on their own? How to explain show and narrate data in short videos</title>
      <link>/project/letdatatalk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/letdatatalk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In recent years and accelerated by the COVID19 crisis, video has become a preferential device for science pedagogics and communication. Scientists increasingly use video in their (digital) lectures and seminars, and to communicate their insights to outsiders. This development is accelerated as people outside science increasingly turn to online video platforms such as YouTube for information retrieval about scientific topics (Allgaier 2019; 2020). Debates around hockey sticks and #flattenthecurve graphs within social networks have also shown that people recently acquired considerable skills to see, interpret and negotiate data - which is commonly referred to as &amp;lsquo;data literacy‘ (Bhargava et al. 2015; Gray et al. 2016).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the researchers, producing such videos is both challenging from a technical and conceptual point of view. What technologies are there to produce and edit videos? How can we get access to such software and other equipment? How does one edit film material? And even more important: how can I tell an interesting and comprehensible story within the video medium? What possibilities are there to show and distribute my content within online and social media platforms?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Geo.X fellows, it is a challenge to explain their highly technical, data-heavy scientific knowledge to people outside their own scientific community of practice, to non-experts and different publics. How to talk about ‚data&amp;rsquo; if the concept of data is not well known to or easily misinterpreted by the audience? How to highlight what is important and to blackbox what is irrelevant to the specific target audience? How to show, represent and explain data? And how to tell as story with data and use metaphors for a better understanding?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the week, participants of the research challenge will learn about, experiment and cope with the challenges to explain, visualize and narrate ‚data&amp;rsquo; using the medium of the video. The fellows will collaboratively produce videos and reflect on the challenges encountered within the process. Adressed elements and aspects during the school:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*Getting inspiration (watching and discussing online videos by scientists)- Narrative strategies for data storytelling
*Getting to know technologies for video production (cameras, sound, editing and visualization software)
*Learn how to use video production software
*Upload and distribute content online&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the school, fellows will have a clearer idea how to use the medium of the video for their own science communication. They may also have produced a short video within the week, alone or in collaboration with colleagues.  The ideas and reflections gathered during the week will be collected in a living document, which may ultimately take the form of a published guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-person&#34;&gt;Contact person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simon Hirsbrunner &amp;amp; Maria Piquer Rodriguez&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;resources&#34;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allgaier, Joachim. „Science and Environmental Communication on YouTube: Strategically Distorted Communications in Online Videos on Climate Change and Climate Engineering“. Frontiers in Communication 4 (2019). &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.3389/fcomm.2019.00036&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.3389/fcomm.2019.00036&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;———. „Science and Medicine on YouTube“. In Second International Handbook of Internet Research, herausgegeben von Jeremy Hunsinger, Matthew M. Allen, und Lisbeth Klastrup, 7–27. Dordrecht: Springer Netherlands, 2020. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-024-1555-1_1&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-94-024-1555-1_1&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bhargava, Rahul, Erica Deahl, Emmanuel Letouzé, Amanda Noonan, David Sangokoya, und Natalie Shoup. „Beyond data literacy: reinventing community engagement and empowerment in the age of data“. Data-Pop Alliance White Paper Series. Data-Pop Alliance (Harvard Humanitarian Initiative, MIT Lad and Overseas Development Institute) and Internews, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gray, Jonathan, Liliana Bounegru, Stefania Milan, und Paolo Ciuccarelli. „Ways of Seeing Data: Toward a Critical Literacy for Data Visualizations as Research Objects and Research Devices“. In Innovative Methods in Media and Communication Research, 227–251. Springer, 2016. &lt;a href=&#34;http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-40700-5_12&#34;&gt;http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-40700-5_12&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website contributions</title>
      <link>/info/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/info/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This website is made with 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/slisovski/GeoX_autumnSchool2020&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;, the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://bookdown.org/yihui/blogdown/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blogdown&lt;/a&gt; R package, and the Academic theme for 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. The infrastructure allows you to directly contribute to the website. If you are familiar with RStudio, R Markdwon and GitHub, you can start immediately. Other options via text editor and git are possible too. However, a short introduction migth help to get you started:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-setup&#34;&gt;Initial setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cloning-the-homepage-repo&#34;&gt;Cloning the homepage repo&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make a github account 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask Simeon (
&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:simeon.lisovski@gmail.com&#34;&gt;simeon.lisovski@gmail.com&lt;/a&gt;) to be added as a collaborator to the repo.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open your terminal (or R studio) and navigate to a directory where you&amp;rsquo;d like to clone the repository.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run this command in your terminal (or in git bash or while you create a blockdown project in RStudio):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone --recursive -j8 https://github.com/slisovski/GeoX_autumnSchool2020.git
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check that you&amp;rsquo;re on the master branch both in the root directory, as well as in the subfolder public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the root directory, run the following commands:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git branch 
cd public
git branch 
cd ../themes/academic
git branch
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should be on the branch &lt;code&gt;master&lt;/code&gt; for all three of them. If not, then type &lt;code&gt;git checkout master&lt;/code&gt; to change the branch (in each of the three directories).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-hugo-not-nessesary-if-you-work-with-rstudio&#34;&gt;Installing &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; (not nessesary if you work with RStudio)&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First, install &lt;code&gt;homebrew&lt;/code&gt; following the instructions 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://brew.sh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current version of the homepage works with hugo version 0.55.5. To install this particular version, run the following commands (see 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fernandomc.com/posts/brew-install-legacy-hugo-site-generator/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this post&lt;/a&gt; for more info).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;brew unlink hugo
brew install https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/homebrew-core/2d7e602ad4c26d1d509e5f6c17fd5911323788a3/Formula/hugo.rb
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-research-project-folder&#34;&gt;The research project folder&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...
├── content
│   ├── home
│   ├── info
│   ├── project
│   └── projects
...
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;: contains markdown files used to render the page
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;home&lt;/code&gt;: all widgets displayed on the first page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;info&lt;/code&gt;: this site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;project&lt;/code&gt;: the project folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;projects&lt;/code&gt;: widget for project site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;change-your-project-site&#34;&gt;Change your project site&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the project folder you will find the index.md file.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make changes (include text, images etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;commit-changes-and-push-to-repository&#34;&gt;Commit changes and push to repository.&lt;/h3&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Killed the Dinosaurs? A comparative extinction selectivity investigation</title>
      <link>/project/dinosaurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/dinosaurs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Machine learning algorithms are rarely utilized in paleontological research, but these algorithms can be used to identify determinants of extinction as well as predicting extinction risk, e.g., key example is the Titanic dataset (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kaggle.com/titanic),&#34;&gt;www.kaggle.com/titanic),&lt;/a&gt; which is used to train data scientists in predicting survivorship from the metadata of passenger information (e.g., gender, wealth, age). This application of decision tree algorithms is important because the ecological selectivity of mass extinctions can reveal critical information on organismic traits as key determinants of extinction and hence the causes of extinction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What killed the dinosaurs? is one of the biggest questions in palaeontological research and on the lips of large number of children. It has been hotly debated for decades that a meteorite wiped them out, but an opposing body of scientists have argued that it was actually climate change that drove dinosaurs to extinction. A bolide impact is only hypothesised to have cause one mass extinction event, whereas climate change has been known to have played an active role in four other mass extinction events. One way we can test if the Dinosaur extinction was caused by something other than climate change, would be to investigate if the extinction selectivity was unique or if it shares a similar trend to other mass extinctions driven by climate change.This project is based on paleontological data collected from around the world and will explore machine learning methods (Fig. 1), and possibly multivariate statistics, to investigate extinction selectivity for three mass extinction events: end-Permian, end-Triassic, and the end-Cretaceous (Dinosaur extinction). The selectivity patterns will then be compared to see if the dinosaur extinction was unique and, therefore, best explained by something other than climate change, i.e., meteorite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data is a spreadsheet of all known marine fossils from the rock record that are known to have existed at the same time as  each extinction event. Each fossil includes information on its taxonomic identification, location that it was collected, age, geological metadata, and seven ecological attributes.From the geological data additional data can be generated, for example geographic range for each species.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;contact-person&#34;&gt;Contact person&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;William Foster (&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:william.foster@ucd.ie&#34;&gt;william.foster@ucd.ie&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LICENSE: CC-BY-SA</title>
      <link>/license/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>/license/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My 
&lt;a href=&#34;/post/&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; are released under a 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0 International License&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;center&gt;
&lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-creative-commons fa-2x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-creative-commons-by fa-2x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;fab fa-creative-commons-sa fa-2x&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
&lt;/center&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentorship</title>
      <link>/mentor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/mentor/</guid>
      <description>


&lt;p&gt;We invite all Geo.X supervisors and seniors to participate in our 2020 Autumn School. Obviously you can be part of the School and attend all sessions as well as sign up for a research challenge. However, you can also become a remote mentor for either a research challenge or a specific topic that you consider important to one or more of the topics (e.g. meta analyses). If you are interested, please sign up using the form below. You will be added as a mentor in the project pages. The idea is, that you will be available for a video chat during an agreed time and day to discuss the progress if the research challenge and provide input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;form name=&#34;contact&#34; class=&#34;contact-form width-normal&#34; action=&#34;/mentor/thank-you&#34; method=&#34;POST&#34; data-netlify=&#34;true&#34;&gt;
    &lt;input type=&#34;hidden&#34; name=&#34;form-name&#34; value=&#34;contact&#34; /&gt;
    
    &lt;!-- Text input--&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;form-group&#34;&gt;
        &lt;label class=&#34;col-md-4 control-label&#34; for=&#34;Name&#34;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;col-md-4&#34;&gt;
            &lt;input id=&#34;contact-form-name&#34; name=&#34;Name&#34; type=&#34;text&#34; placeholder=&#34;Name&#34; class=&#34;form-control input-md&#34; required=&#34;&#34; autocomplete=&#34;off&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;!-- Text input--&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;form-group&#34;&gt;
        &lt;label class=&#34;col-md-4 control-label&#34; for=&#34;Email&#34;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;col-md-4&#34;&gt;
            &lt;input id=&#34;contact-form-email&#34; name=&#34;Email&#34; type=&#34;email&#34; placeholder=&#34;Email Address&#34; class=&#34;form-control input-md&#34; required=&#34;&#34; autocomplete=&#34;off&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;!-- Textarea --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;form-group&#34;&gt;
        &lt;label class=&#34;col-md-4 control-label&#34; for=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/label&gt;
        &lt;textarea class=&#34;form-control&#34; id=&#34;contact-form-message&#34; name=&#34;Message&#34; placeholder=&#34;Please type in the research challenge or up to 3 keywords.&#34; rows=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&lt;/textarea&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;!-- Button --&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;form-group&#34;&gt;
        &lt;button type=&#34;submit&#34; value=&#34;Submit&#34; id=&#34;Form-submit&#34;&gt;Submit&lt;/button&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/form&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions please contact the school organizers (Lisa, Tabea, Teresa, Niklas, Simeon).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
